http://www.kelty.com/privacy-policy/

Updated August 1, 2020
This Privacy Policy states how information about you, including your Personal Data, is collected, used, and disclosed by Exxel Outdoors when you access or use our websites or otherwise interact with us.  Exxel Outdoors may revise this Privacy Policy and we encourage you to review it frequently to stay informed about our information practices and the ways you can help protect your privacy.
PROTECTING YOUR PRIVACY IS OUR PRIORITY
We respect and protect your privacy when using our websites.  This Privacy Statement applies to our own websites that we control.  If you provide or we obtain your Personal Data about you from any source, we treat your Personal Data according to this Privacy Policy.
PERSONAL DATA WE COLLECT ABOUT YOU
When you visit our websites, set up an account, initiate a transaction, submit a request, apply for a position, etc., you may be asked to provide certain information, including, your name, address, title, phone number, e-mail address, credit card information, and line of business. You may also be providing us with data regarding your devices including, your IP address, your location, your data usage, your client or supplier account, etc.  We may also collect information related to you, and your family members, such as age, gender and civil status. This information and data may be Personal Data under applicable Privacy Laws.
WHY WE OBTAIN YOUR PERSONAL DATA AND LEGAL BASES FOR USE AND RETENTION
Please consult the table below to see the categories of Personal Data we may collect about you, why we process (collect, use, store, etc.) your Personal Data, the legal grounds for such processing (where applicable) and the relevant maximum retention period.
Reasons for Retaining
Types of Personal Data
Legal Reasons
Retention Period
Customer Information (including account management, providing services, billing, customer support, personalized customer experience, etc.)
Name, address, city, state, postal code, country, phone number, email address, IP location, website usage, email preferences, product registration data
Manage our business and websites
Comply with legal requirements in processing your data
Enter and perform contracts agreements with you
Up to 10 years following the date of the last order or ending of contract term, unless a longer period is required by law or for court action
Direct Sales to Customers (including account management, providing services, billing, customer support, personalized customer experience, etc.)
Name, address, city, state, postal code, country, phone number, email address, IP location, website usage, email preferences, shipping address, transaction details
Manage our business and websites
Comply with legal requirements in processing your data
Enter and perform contracts agreements with you
Up to 10 years following the date of the last order or ending of contract term, unless a longer period is required by law or for court action
Prevent Fraud and Illegal Activities (e.g. identity theft, money-laundering, etc.)
Name, address, phone number, email address, IP location, website usage, transaction details
Manage our business and websites
Enter and perform contracts agreements with you
Up to 10 years following the date of the last order or ending of contract term, unless a longer period is required by law or for court action
Direct marketing (including email marketing, promotions, surveys, etc.)**
Name, address, city, state, postal code, country, phone number, email address, IP location, website usage, email preferences, gender, interests
Manage our business and websites
Enter and perform contracts agreements with you
When you consent or opt-in where required
Up to the date we process your your withdrawal of consent to direct marketing communications or when your information is no longer needed for marketing purposes
Managing Suppliers
Name, address, phone number, email address, IP location, transaction details, financial data (bank account and credit card details, etc.), shipping address, credit history
Manage our business and websites
Comply with legal requirements in processing your data
Enter and perform contracts agreements with you
Up to 10 years following the date of the last order or ending of contract term, unless a longer period is required by law or for court action
Security of persons and assets
Name, address, phone number, email address, IP location, transaction details, financial data (bank account and credit card details, etc.), shipping address, credit history
Manage our business and websites
Comply with legal requirements in processing your data
Enter and perform contracts agreements with you
Up to 10 years following the date of the last order or ending of contract term, unless a longer period is required by law or for court action
Complying with and managing legal requirements
Name, address, phone number, email address, IP location, transaction details
Manage our business and websites
Comply with legal requirements in processing your data
Enter and perform contracts agreements with you
To establish or defend legal obligations, processes or claims.
Up to 10 years following the date of the last order or ending of contract term, unless a longer period is required by law or for court action
Product/service improvement & business intelligence
Name, address, phone number, email address, IP location, website usage, transaction details
Manage our business and websites
When you consent
Up to 10 years from the date product was discontinued
* Retention periods vary depending on the type of document containing the Personal Data.
We keep your Personal Data while we are providing you with our products and services. In addition, we keep your Personal Data for any of the following reasons: (a) to comply with legal record keeping requirements; (b) to have a record of how we communicated or interacted with you; (c) to respond to inquiries or claims made by you or on your behalf; (d) to keep a record of our high standards of serving our customers;  (e) to be able to operate our business processes.  We will retain your Personal Data to the extent allowed by laws and regulations, then securely delete it.  We may retain anonymous data without reference to identifying information.
HOW WE SHARE YOUR PERSONAL DATA WITH OTHERS
We may disclose your Personal Data to certain types of entities and purposes including: to comply with legal obligation such as court orders, search warrants, subpoenas and to our company affiliates, suppliers, resellers, advertising groups, partner companies and service providers.  We strive to keep such disclosures to those that are reasonably necessary and subject to terms set out in this Privacy Policy.  Although we do not intend to sell your Personal Data, certain applicable laws may be interpreted in such a way as to characterize some disclosures as a “sale”.
We may disclose your Personal Data to our insurance advisers and carriers as reasonably necessary for the purposes of obtaining or maintaining professional advice, insurance coverage, risk management, or for conducting defense of legal claims in any court or other legal proceedings.
We may disclose your Personal Data to our payment services providers to complete financial transactions. Transaction data will be provided to our payment services providers only to the extent necessary for processing your payments, refunds, and managing complaints and queries relating to such payments and refunds.  In the event of bankruptcy or a sale or transfer of all or a portion of our business or assets, an acquisition, merger or divestiture, we reserve the right to transfer your Personal Data.
We may disclose your Personal Data if disclosure is necessary to investigate or enforce this potential violations of this Privacy Policy, our other policies for providing services, contracts with you, respond to claims regarding violations of third party rights, respond to your requests for customer service, and/or protect the rights, property or personal safety of our employees, agents and affiliates, website users and/or the public. This includes exchanging information with other entities, agencies, companies and organizations for fraud protection, spam/malware prevention.
With the exception of the terms in this Privacy Policy, we do not sell, rent, or otherwise share your Personal Data with any third parties outside of Exxel Outdoors or with our affiliated companies for monetary or other valuable consideration.
SENSITIVE PERSONAL DATA
Unless specifically requested by us or required by law, we ask that you not send or disclose to us Sensitive Personal Data such as your religion, ethnicity, biometrics, genetics, health, political opinions, ideological beliefs, criminal background, union membership, court or administrative proceedings.
INTERNATIONAL DATA TRANSFERS
Exxel Outdoors is based in the United States with local and international sales with customers, offices and facilities in worldwide locations including the European Union/EEA, Latin America, Asia, etc.  In certain circumstances Your Personal Data may be transferred to those affiliated offices and third-party service providers who may process your Personal Data on our behalf, including e-marketing service providers, hosting providers, etc. The privacy laws in other countries may differ from the United States.
If you are a resident of a country other than the United State, the privacy laws in your country may differ from others and some may not provide protections equivalent to those in your country of residence.  We may need to process your information or transfer your information to the United States or other countries.
If you reside in a country in the European Union (EU/EEA) and we need to transfer your Personal Data to a country which has been deemed to have an inadequate level of protection for Personal Data, we will implement available safeguards in accordance with the EU requirements.
YOUR RIGHTS ABOUT ACCESS AND CONTROL OF PERSONAL DATA
Your rights regarding Your Personal Data are subject to local law in the jurisdiction where you reside.
If you reside in the EU/EEA, upon submitting a verified request, you may have the right to receive supplemental information about your Personal Data and/or a copy of your Personal Data.  You may request to correct and/or update inaccurate or out-of-date Personal Data.  You may have the right to have your Personal Data erased or restrict its processing. You may have the right to object to specific types of processing of your Personal Data. You may have the right to request a portable copy of your Personal Data.  You may be subject to certain limitations such as data portability does not apply to paper records, must not prejudice the rights of others, and may not apply to sensitive company information.
You have the right to submit a complaint with an authority designated by the foreign country.  You may have the right to have contact with a person rather than only automated processing.  If you have such a request, you may contact privacy@exxel.com for further information.
You may be asked to provide information to help us verify your identity prior to responding to your inquiry.  If your request is not valid, is repetitive or excessive pursuant to the applicable law, Exxel Outdoors may request a reasonable fee for processing your request(s).
If you are a California resident, you may request a notification of your rights.  Upon submitting a verified request, you may also have the right to know what categories of information we collect about you and whether and how such information was sold or disclosed to third parties for a business purpose including marketing during the one-year period immediately prior to your request.  You may request the identities of the parties that received your personal information for direct marketing purposes.  You may opt-out of the sale of your personal information. You may request the deletion of your personal information maintained by us.  You may request to a portable copy of personal information.
You may not be discriminated against for exercising your rights under the law.
If you wish to exercise any of these rights, please contact privacy@exxel.com.
To opt-out of the sale of your personal information contact privacy@exxel.com.
This Privacy Statement does not create, extend or modify any EU Data Subject rights, California consumer rights, or Exxel Outdoors obligations, except as provided by the GDPR and CCPA.
DATA PROTECTION CONTROLLER CONTACT INFORMATION
Exxel Outdoors’ Data Protection Director may be contacted at:
Attn: Data Protection Director1 International CourtBroomfield, Colorado 80021
PERSONAL DATA SUBMITTED BY CHILDREN
We do not knowingly solicit, collect, process or sell personal information from children under age 13 without parental consent, unless permitted by law. If we become aware that we have collected personal information from a child under age 13 without parental consent or unless otherwise permitted by law, we will delete it in accordance with applicable law. If you believe that a child may have provided us with Personal Data without parental consent or otherwise not permitted by law, please contact privacy@exxel.com.
California consumers – We do not knowingly solicit, collect, process or sell personal information of consumers who are 16 years old or younger without prior parental authorization as required by law. California consumers under the age of 13 years must have a parent or guardian consent to the sale of the minor’s personal information. However, if the California consumer is between the ages of 13 and 16 years old, the minor may provide opt-in consent to the sale of their personal information.
EU Residents – We do not collect, or process personal data related to EU Data Subjects under the age of 16 without explicit consent from a parent or guardian. Our sites directed toward children will ask for age verification and require consent as appropriate.
TRACKING TECHNOLOGIES INCLUDING COOKIES AND WEB BEACONS
Exxel Outdoors’ sites use Cookies. Cookies are text files containing small amounts of information which are downloaded to your device when you visit a website that allow a website to recognize a user’s device. Cookies improve the use of our sites through various website functions such as allowing users to “log in” and navigate more efficiently and remembering your preferences such as language. Cookies can also help with making the content and advertisements you see online more relevant to your interests.  Our newsletters and emails may include web beacons so that we know if the messages and links therein have been clicked.
Our business partners may sometimes set web beacons and Cookies on our site. Third-party social media buttons may log certain information such as your IP address, referring website addresses, browser type, and language. If you are logged in to those social media sites, they may also link such collected information with your profile information on that site.
To learn more about cookies or how to opt-out of cookies from your browser, visit www.allaboutcookies.org for further information. If you disable cookies, some of the features on our sites may not function as a result.
SECURITY
We have implemented commercially reasonable safeguards to maintain security, but no system can be perfect.  You are responsible for maintaining the secrecy of your credentials that can be used to access any account or service with Exxel Outdoors. If you suspect any unauthorized activity, please report the matter to us immediately by contacting privacy@exxel.com.
LINKS TO THIRD PARTY SITES
We may collect your information from third party sites, including when you log in through a third-party site such as Facebook, Instagram, Snapchat, LinkedIn, Twitter, etc. We may also disclose information collected from third parties to customize ads and to manage and facilitate messaging on third party sites. Please note that when you unsubscribe from our marketing email there may be a delay in the discontinuation of our ads directed to you on third party sites.
DO NOT TRACK
Exxel Outdoors does not track its customers over time and across third party websites to provide targeted advertising and therefore does not respond to Do Not Track (DNT) signals. Some third-party sites do keep track of your browsing activities when they serve you content, which enables them to tailor what they present to you. If you are visiting such sites, you may be able to set the DNT signal on your browser so that third parties (particularly advertisers) know you do not want to be tracked.
USING MOBILE AND OTHER DEVICES
Exxel Outdoors, our affiliates and third parties that we have retained, may collect and store unique identifiers matched to your mobile device in order to deliver customized ads or content while you use our Sites, navigate the internet, to deliver location-based services and advertising, or to identify you in a unique manner across devices or browsers. In order to customize these ads or content, we, or third parties, may collect Personal Data, e.g., your email address, or data passively collected from you such as your device identifier, location, or IP address. Your mobile devices may allow you to turn off location services.  To adjust the privacy and security setting on your device, please refer to instructions provided by the device manufacturer or your service provider.
EMAIL MARKETING COMMUNICATIONS
You may be receiving emails from us or our affiliates.  If you are an existing customer or, if required by applicable law, you have provided consent or have not directed us not to send you advertising or marketing email messages, we may send you emails and/or mail to keep you updated on our products and services. If you wish to stop receiving marketing email messages you can stop them by clicking the “unsubscribe” link in any of our emails, or access your account and change your settings and preferences, or contact privacy@exxel.com. It may take several business days to process your opt-out/unsubscribe your requests, which we will do as quickly as possible.  We will not stop any communications connected with services such as order updates.
TEXT MESSAGING
If you have opted in to receive text messages and alerts by sharing your mobile device number, we may send you text messages regarding your account, alerts, to investigate or prevent fraud, etc., including using autodialed technology.  Occasionally we may provide you with the ability to send a text message to a specific short code and provide an opt-in to receive future text messages. Your opt-in request provides us with your mobile phone number. If you choose to opt-in, you agree that we may send messages to the mobile device regarding offers, services, products and promotions.
You may choose to opt-out from our text messages and alerts at any time by replying “STOP” to the message you received, following which you will not receive any additional text messages to your mobile phone.  We will no longer be able to text or call your mobile phone with important messages regarding your account or transactions with us.  If there is an emergency or account question, we will attempt to contact you by email, landline phone, or mail. It is not necessary that you opt-in to text messages and alerts to use our Sites and services. If you do opt-in, standard text messaging charges may apply.
CHANGES TO OUR PRIVACY POLICY
We reserve the right to add, change, or modify this privacy policy at any time which we will do in accordance with applicable law.  Material changes will be posted to this website and you are responsible for reviewing our Privacy Policy each time you provide Personal Data to us as the Privacy Policy may have changed since the last time you used our Sites or services.
CONTACT US
If you have questions about this Privacy Policy or Exxel Outdoors’ and practices, you may contact privacy@exxel.com.
×
×
